阿杰
Kit!
- 小马 - 来了
Come! Coming!
碟子还给你
The plate
警官
Sir!
好不好吃呀
Taste good?
你没什么吧
Are you alright?
你会不会看呀
Can you read it?
什么
What?
不会看就别充内行
Don't pretend
- 宋先生 你好 - 嗨 罗斯先生
How are you! Hi, Russ
谢谢
Thanks
就是这个
That's it!
做得很好 一流水准
That's great, first class
有机会一起喝酒
Why don't we go out for a drink sometimes
跟你做生意非常愉快
It's pleasure doing business with you
你真能掰啊
Good!
你的英文进步了
Your English is improved
会说 Of course了
Even know of course
Of course
Of course!
- 宋先生 早 - 嗨 早
- Good morning. Mark Mr Sung Good morning
宋先生 早晨
Good morning, Mr Sung
小马哥 早
Good morning, Mark
小马哥 叫得真好听啊
That's good
姚叔叔
Mr Yiu
阿豪 你回来了 顺利吗
Ho, you are back! Everything OK?
- 顺利吗 - 顺利
Everything OK?
那些洋人蛮爽快的
Those foreigners are easy going
不是每个洋人都这么好商量的
Not all of them are as good as they are
你的缺点就是太容易相信人了
Your weakness is too easy to believe someone
多谢
Thanks!
阿成是吗 坐
You are Shing? Sit…
不用了 我站着好啦
No, thanks. It's better for me to stand
早啊 陈小姐
Good morning. Linda!
唉 玫瑰
Rose!
阿成 你多跟豪哥学习学习
There's a lot, you can learn from Ho
他很够义气的
He's excellent
对 豪哥有很多东西我是学不来的
But I'll never be as good as him
你别看小马吊儿郎当
Though mark is frivolous
但他是很忠心的
But he is loyal
是啊 他很照顾我的
Yes, he takes good care of me
说什么呢
What are you talking about?
老板在夸你呢
Nothing. Just talking about you!
是吗
Really?
你弟弟阿杰今天毕业呀
Your brother, Kit, graduates today
对 我忘了 买礼物给他呐
Oh! Yes. I forgot to buy him a present
姚叔叔 我先走了
I've got to go now
阿豪 后天去台湾 你带阿成一块去
Ho. Take Shing with you tomorrow to Taiwan
给年青人一个机会嘛
Give the kid a chance
台湾呀 你以为柴湾呀
Taiwan. Don't mistake it with Chai Wan?
我行走江湖几十年都不敢去台湾
Though I've been in this field for years I'm still afraid to go
你知道为什么
Do you know why?
是因为扁钻多 西瓜刀多
Too much fighting
喝啤酒也把你喝死啊
and drink
别拿他开玩笑了
Don't fool him
是啦
OK
阿杰毕业了 送个女人给他嘛
Give Kit a hooker for a graduation present
我自己虽然不好 我不会让他学坏的
I'm no good, but I want him to be a good citizen
总比叫妓好呀
But it's better to have a whore
我要看着他读博士
I want to see him to be a PhD
看着他在教堂结婚
Getting married
看着他洞房 看着他生孩子
And having his own baby
那你不是比新界的牛还要辛苦
Then you'll be as busy as a buffalo
人家说嘴巴不干净
People say, one will step on shit
入电梯就会踩狗屎
with a big mouth
你先进吧
You go in first
你先进呀
You first
我才不呐
I won't
一起踩吧
We will go in together
别动 我是警察
Hold it. We are police
别动呀
Freeze
把头转过去
Tune th head...
大家都有枪 你不给我面子
Both of us have guns If you don't respect me…
我也不会给你面子的
I won't
看看谁不给谁好了
See who doesn't respecting the others
痒死我了
So ticklish
不要
Don't…
不敢了
Please…
我考上警官了
You'll surprise
我已经考了帮办了 意外吧
I am an Inspector, surprise!
那你要用心去做
You have to work hard
起码要做到警司才够威
At least you've got to be a superintendent
小齐
Jackie!
有空就来帮忙照顾爸爸的
Do you...
我大哥
My brother
嗨
Hi!
这样照顾爸爸就惨咯
Taking care of dad in this way!
麻烦你
Thanks a lot
不要客气
Don't mention it
我够钟要去考试了
I've got to sit for an exam
又换画 这个应该是正场了吧
Are you going steady
先看看午夜场的反应再说吧
Don't know yet!
你说过送我的 快点呀
You said you'll go with me! Hurry up!
我是想留下照顾爸爸的 不过
I really want to stay… But…
用不着多解释了 去吧
No need to explain.
我先走了
- I go first
- Go!
对不起
Sorry
我们走吧
Let's go!
快点呀
Quick!
拜拜
Bye!
爸爸
Dad.
你应该要收手啦
You should quit
你弟弟一直不知道你是干哪行的
Your brother doesn't know what you have been doing
我记得你们小时候
Still remember
他跟你玩兵捉贼
You two played cop & thief when you were kids
他猜输了
He almost lost
他死也吵着要做兵
But he still wanted to be a cop
我不想你们两兄弟长大了
I don't want you to play
还玩这种游戏
the same game again
就当是为了你的弟弟吧
For your brother
好吗
Promise!
好
Yes!
差不多了
That's better
对不起 堵车了
Excuse me… Traffic is so bad
我是张小齐
Yes. Traffic jam, I am Jackie
请给我一次机会吧
Sir, Traffic jam
给她一个机会吧 好不好
Traffic jam
求求你了 求求你了 给她一次机会吧
Are you alright?
- 给她一次机会吧 - 好好好 行
Give her a chance please? OK…
行了 快上啊 上啊
Go!
有了身孕还让人撞着 真太惨了
So pity
喂 评判团 请听听
Listen. Judges
对不起
Sorry
都是你 害得我一上台就出丑
It's you… You made me so embarrassed
你一点都帮不了我
You spoiled everything
我怎么帮你呢
How...?
而且黑面神也没说你不行
They didn't say you are out
你怎知道没希望呢
How do you know you'll fail?
还给我呀
Give it back to me
这次真的什么希望都没有啦
I will really fail this time
决定了
Are you sure?
干完这次就收手了
This will be my last time
为了阿杰
Because of Kit?
明天台湾那宗买卖 你不要去了
Don't come with me to Taiwan tomorrow
万一我出了事 这边也有你照顾呀
Any goes wrong, you here to handle it
以后兄弟们由你带着
Then they will follow you
那一定会垮的
I can't do it
这位子让阿成坐好了
Then Shing will do it
你看他像阿尔柏仙奴似的
He resembles Al Pacino
小马哥 别玩我嘛
Please don't fool me, Mark
豪哥 没有你我们撑不住这个局面
Ho, we can't do without you
我还有很多事情要向你学习的
I'm not mature yet
你想学就有得学了吗
Don't expect too much
别以为整天看那些黑手党的书
Don't think you can be the Big Brother
就可以当老大了
by reading the books about underworld
你试过让人用枪口对着头没有
Anyone ever point a gun at you?
没有
No!
十二年前
12 years ago…
十二年了吧
12 years,
我跟豪哥第一次带货去印尼
Ho and I went to Indonesia the first time
那边的老大请我们去夜总会吃饭
We had a dinner at a club with their Big Brother
我讲错了一句话 得罪了那边的老大
I said something wrong
跟着就有两枝枪指着我的头
Suddenly 2 guns were pointing at my head
要我把整瓶威士忌喝光了
and I was ordered to drink a bottle of whisky
我吓得撒尿 真的撒尿了
I was so scared
豪哥真行
Ho is really great
他替我把整瓶威士忌喝光了
He drank it for me
不喝还好 喝了更惨了
But there was even worse
跟着四枝枪指着我的头
4 guns were pointing at me then…
知不知道要我喝什么
Do you know what they asked me to drink?
喝尿
Urine!
在夜总会里头喝尿
Drank urine in the club
学习 这才叫学习
Learning! That's what you call learning
我们第一单生意就这样做成了
That's our first deal
过去的事 不要再提了
That's history Don't talk about it anymore
不
No!
我长这么大 从来没哭过
Never cried since I was a kid
那次是我第一次流眼泪
That's the first time I cried
再不会让人家用枪指着我的头
No more...
厉害吧
That's good!
小心点
Be careful
多练习打沙包吧
Hitting a sand bag more often
我明天要走了
I've to go tomorrow
又定期失踪啦
Regular disappearance
我会很快回来的
I'll be back soon
我走了之后要多点照顾爸爸
When I'm away, take care of dad
放心吧
I will
小心身体
Take care!
我会的
Yes!
他们来了 快闪
They're coming
小心 有点不对劲
Be careful, there's something wrong here
你怎么知道
How do you know?
直觉
Intuition
宋先生 辛苦了 你好
Mr Sung, how are you!
老汪呢
Where is Mr Wang?
他生病了 我是他的侄儿
He's not feeling well I'm his nephew
他叫我来代替他接货
He asked me to replace him
你好
How are you!
他生什么病
What kind of illness he has got?
宋先生 我们进去慢慢讲
Mr Sung, let's go in and talk
其实也没什么病
Nothing serious
只是最近清专案来得凶
Just hiding out
暂时避一避而已
for a while
来来 请喝杯茶 路上辛苦了
Have a cup of tea
好 谢谢
Thanks!
宋先生 这边请
Mr Sung, this way please!
人年纪大了 就什么病都怕
Scared of everything when you are getting old
请坐呀
Please sit
我们还是不要浪费时间了
Don't waste time!
呼叫总部
Attention, head quarters
请调查一下车牌号码北市1086379
Please check a car Taipei 1086379
我们觉得它形迹可疑
It's a bit suspicious
宋先生 你真守信用
We know you're reliable
我在西门町混的时候 就很崇拜你了
I respected you when I was a kid
你相信吗
Do you believe that?
居然有人出双倍价钱要我了啦你
Someone paid me double to kill you
他神经病 我会是这种人吗
He's crazy, who do they think I am?
我拿钱给你呀
I give you money
警察来了
Police!
喂
Hello!
伯伯
Uncle
一叶轻舟去 人隔万重山呀
We'll be miles away
宋子豪在台湾杀了我们几个弟兄
Sung kill some of our men in Taiwan
现在被警方通缉
He is wanted by the Police
老大怕他泄露我们的秘密
Big brother is worried that Ho might talk his secret
请你老人家跟我走一趟
Please come with me
我是不想动粗的
I don't want to be rude
你们这班混蛋
You son of a bitch
如果你们害了我的儿子
If you hurt my son
我不会放过你们的
I won't let you off
跑 快跑
Run!
你干什么
What are you doing?
不要呀
No!
不要迫我
Don't push me!
搭错线了
Wrong number
走呀 伯伯
Go. Uncle!
伯伯
Uncle!
小齐 发生什么事了
Jackie, what's happening?
阿杰 你小心点
Be careful, Kit?
爸爸 不要出来
Dad, don't come out
我打你 爸 我打你 爸
Dad, please don't
爸 爸
Dad!
- 阿杰 你千万要原谅你哥哥呀 - 爸
Kit, you have to forgive your brother!
是谁出卖了我
Who betrayed me?
你
You?
豪哥 如果是我出卖了你
Ho, if I did
又怎么会跟你一起呢
I wouldn't be here with you now
这一次 不知道能不能逃出去
I don't know if I can escape this time
豪哥 你干什么 豪哥
Ho, what are you doing?
我要去自首
I'm going to surrender
你不能去呀 豪哥
You can't
不要去 千万不要出去呀
Please don't
豪哥 你千万不要走出去
Please don't go
豪哥 不要 豪哥 你不要出去
No
豪哥 不要呀
No!…
快走
Run!
豪哥
Ho…
走啦
Go away
我不想多连累一个朋友
I don't want to implicate another friend
砖窑那边有枪声
There's gun shots in the cavern
你走呀
You go
我不走
No
我叫你走呀
I insist you go
别动
Stand and don't move
把枪放下
Put down the gun
听见没有 把枪放下
Did you hear me? Put down the gun
想不到以前的已经不存在了
There's no more rules in the world
身边的人没有一个可以相信
You can't trust any one today
小汪这个废物 是我的亲侄子
Even my nephew, Wang
居然连我也出卖
betrayed me
他勾结香港的新势力
He joined up with a new HK gang
企图谋夺我的生意
to try to take over my business
宋子豪 就是这样栽在他的手里
As a result, we've lost Ho
在道义上 我们绝对尊重讲信义的朋友
We respect a faithful man
但是绝不纵容出卖朋友的人
but not a traitor
喂
Hello!
好
Yes!
今天晚上他在枫林阁酒家
He will be in Fung Lim Restaurant tonight
怎么样
What are you gong to do?
还有什么需要我帮忙的
Do you need any help?
要不要派几个人给你
Do you need my men?
保重
Take care!
谢谢
Thanks!
队长 队长
Chief  What's this?
- 队长 - 在里面
Chief, Inside here
我才不怕呐
I'm not scared
我老大一定会找律师来保释我出去的
My boss will post bail for me
够英雄的就不用手枪
If you've the gut,
跟我来比划一下
fight with me without a gun
看看是谁强
See who is stronger?
宋警官 什么事
Sir, what's happening?
没事
Nothing!
- 宋警官 - 什么案子
Sung, what's the charge?
运毒拒捕跟袭警
Drug trafficking, attacking the police
- 宋警官你都敢惹 - 先给他录口供
How dare you insult Inspector Sung Take down his statement
谢谢
Thanks!
怎么样 外面的空气感觉不一样吧
How's that? Feeling different!
我送你
Can I give you a lift?
谢谢 我们路不同
No, thanks We are not going the same way
我佩服你
I admire you
为了朋友
Because of your friends
三年来 你一句话都不说
You kept quiet
可笑的是你人在里面
That's ridiculous. You were behind bars
外面的伪钞还是照印不误
The counterfeiting racket is still strong
谢谢
Thanks!
我早已经不问江湖事了
I'm not involved anymore
你告诉你的朋友
Tell your friends
三年前那案子还没了结
The case is still open
我不会放过他的
I won't let him off
想重新做人 是要经过考验的
A bad guy for a day Will never be a good guy again
再见
Bye!
I'll never come back again
停车
Stop!
阿杰 你冷静点
Kit, cool down
不要打呀
Stop fighting
阿杰 不要打呀
Kit, stop
不要让我再看到你
Don't let me see you again
经理
Manager!
这里没有经理
There's no manager here
我叫坚叔 找我什么事
I'm Ken, are you looking for me?
坚叔 台湾的忠伯叫我来找你的
Uncle Chung, asked me to come see you
我在台湾做生意的时候
When I was doing business in Taiwan…
坐牢就坐牢啦 做什么生意
Doing business? You were in jail!
这封信 忠伯叫我亲手交给你
Mr Chung asked me to give you this letter
忠伯真不够意思
Chung, he never does anything good
谁叫我跟他做朋友呢
But we are friends
坐过牢的人是很难找事做的
It's so difficult to get a job for an ex-con
有谁愿意请囚犯的
No one will hire an ex-con
用不着垂头丧气
Don't feel depressed
这里每个兄弟都是坐过牢的
All these guys were prisoner before
不过都改过自新了
But...
有些人喜欢收养孤儿
Some people like to adopt orphans,
我这个人呢 喜欢收留囚犯
I like to take care of ex-cons
因为我也尝过坐牢滋味
Because I was in prison too
各位同事 这位弟兄刚来报到
Everybody, here's a new man
大家要多多照顾他
Take care of him
他叫 你叫什么
He is… you are…
宋子豪
Sung Tse Ho
豪哥
Ho brother!
不要这样叫 叫阿豪就行了
Just call me Ho
拍马屁啊 趁机会偷懒啊
Social gathering?
不用工作了吗
Back to work
白送薪金给你们的
I'm not paying you for doing nothing
- 有没有营业驾照啊 - 没有
Do you have a driving license? No
我不管你考到又好 考不到也好
Whether you pass the exam or not…
你就在这里委屈一下
You can stay
坚叔 你真是太好了
Thanks, Ken
你不用多说话了 这里没有老大的
Don't mention it. There's no Boss here
- 拿去吃午饭吧 - 谢谢
- Take it for lunch - Thanks
小马
Mark!
你写给我的信 怎么不是这样说的
That's not what you told me in your letter
就算打断了我的一双腿
Even I break my legs,
也偿还不了你
I can't pay you back
傻瓜 是我自己倒霉 不关你的事
It's not your fault
再看到你真开心
I'm so glad to see you again
没见这么久
Haven't seen you for so long
你还那么帅
You're still looking the same
小马 这里已经不是你跟我的世界
Mark. This isn't our world anymore
你还留在这里干什么
Why are you still here?
我等了你三年 三年了
I've waited for you for 3 years
我们可以从头再来过
Let's start all over again
你不用管我 看着你的弟弟吧
Don't bother me Pay attention to your brother
最近他每天盯着阿成 越来越危险
He's following Shing everyday That's very dangerous
你们到底都是亲兄弟
You're brothers
阿杰 我们全体都知道你很能干
Kit, we all know you are good at your work
我本来想推荐你升级
I recommended your promotion,
可是上级不批准
but it's rejected
为什么
Why?
这个人你应该很熟识
This guy, you know him very well
三年前以为他失了踪
He disappeared 3 years ago
最近他在台湾坐完牢回来
He's back after being released
from prison in Taiwan
又跟那班旧兄弟搭上了
and got back with his old partners again
那跟我有什么关系
It's none of my business
局里正调查黑社会混入警方的事
We're investigating underworld activities
而且最不喜欢
and none of their family members
警务人员的家属是黑社会份子
would be related
你明白了吗
Understand?
我执行职务的时候
When I carry out my order
根本没想过有这么一个哥哥的
I've never thought of my brother
宋子杰
Kit!
成老大的案子 你不用再管了
You're not in Shing's case anymore
我怕你会误了大事
Or you'll spoil the whole matter
- 宋憼官 今天晚上成老大跟泰国人 - 阿南
Sung, Shing will meet those Thai tonight… Nam!
各位兄弟 大家干一杯
Bottom up
小马哥
Mark
叫豪哥说吧 他比我威风
Tell us about your stories Let Ho say it
最多出价一千八百万 不能再加的了
Must...
宋子豪他们在外面
Mr. Song....
谢谢 生啤酒
Draught beer, please
老大在那边
This way please
豪哥
Ho!
怎么回来了也不通知我呀
How come you didn't inform us you're back
太不够朋友了吧
You shouldn't do that
想当年我们都是好兄弟啊
We were good brothers once
是不是 小马哥
Is that right, Mark?
豪哥 要是没有你照顾我
Ho, if you didn't take care of me
我也不会有今天呀
I would never have what I have now
哪里 你有今天
Oh no
是靠你自己的本事啊
You deserve it
我有什么本事
I don't have the ability
小马哥把位子给我而已
It's Mark who gave me the chance
小马哥以后有什么要帮忙的
Mark, if you need my help in the future
尽管说
Just say so
不要说废话了 来 喝酒
Don't bullshit. Let's drink
你可真照顾兄弟呀
You have to take care of our brothers
Cheers!
这一杯是给我的脚喝的
This is for my leg
开心
Happy
豪哥 有空就来看看我
Come to see me when you're free
我们有很多事要谈的
There's a lot we can talk
我没兴趣
I'm not interested
你会有兴趣的
You will be
我先走了
I have to go
宋子豪
Sung Tse Ho!
跟我出去
Follow me
干什么你
What are you doing?
成老大跟你讲了些什么
What did Shing tell you?
废话
Bullshit!
你不要耍我了
Don't fool me!
到底是谈生意还是讲废话
Business or bullshit?
真的是废话
Bullshit, really
是不是后天有货到
Is there something arriving the day after?
不知道
Don't know
在哪里卸货 什么时候卸货
Where to load and when?
不知道
Don't know
你什么都不知道 你算什么大哥呀
How can you be a Big Brother knowing nothing?
阿杰
Kit!
不许叫我名字 叫我警官
Don't call me Kit, call me inspector!
警官 我没有当大哥已经很久了
I'm not a Big Brother anymore
在哪里工作
Where do you work?
联合计程车公司
United Taxi Co
正当行业呀
Decent business
开计程车去打劫呀
Robbing with a taxi?
住在哪里
Where do you live?
联合计程车公司
United Taxi Co
竟然有人肯收留你这个贼
Someone still accepted you thief
臭小子 贼 没名字你叫的吗
Thief… Doesn't he have a name?
你别以为有枪就了不起 你
Don't think you are great to have a gun
你再管闲事 我一枪打死你这个跛子
I'll shoot you down, cripple
小子 不要用枪指着我的头
Don't point at my head with a gun
你够胆就开枪打死我好了
If you've got the guts,
开枪 开枪啦
then shoot me…
阿杰
Kit!
警官 我知道我欠你很多
Sir, I know I owe you too much
你给我一次机会好不好
Give me a chance!
给你一个机会
Give you a chance?
我求求你给我一个机会呀
I beg you to give me one!
你知不知道我为了你
Do you know because of you
连升职的机会也没有呀
I lost my chance of promotion
因为你是黑社会
Because you are a member of the triad
你们千万别离开香港
Don't leave HK
我一定会回来找你们的
I'll be back to get you
要不要三请四请的 来来 喝茶
Do you need an invitation for a cup of tea
多谢坚叔
Thanks!
慢着 在薪水里边扣除的
I will deduct it from your salary
你真小器呀你
You are mean
要不然我怎能养老婆呀
Otherwise How can I support my family?
你说得对
You're right
那边有个女孩盯着你看 蛮漂亮的
There's a beautiful girl staring at you Your girlfriend?
- 进来坐 - 不用了
Please come in! No!
我想你帮我一个忙
I want your help
你可不可以暂时离开香港
Can you leave HK for a while?
我不想看到阿杰快要精神崩溃
I don't want to see Kit getting mad
他受不了这个压力 我也受不了
He can't take this pressure, neither can I
我想 你暂时离开会对他好过一点
So I think it's better for you to be away for a while
我不会离开
I won't leave!
我要让阿杰亲眼看着我重新做人
I want Kit to see that I'm in my new life
你给我一个机会
Can you give me a chance
让我做给他看好不好
to show it to him?
你以为我不想再跟他开开心心
Don't you see I want to skate
一起溜冰 骑单车吗
Riding bicycle with him too?
我也不想失去了这个弟弟
I don't want to lose this brother
豪哥
Ho!
你不要站在这里 进去吧
Don't stay here, go in!
你站在这儿会碍事的
There's no use just staying here
阿豪的事他自己会解决的 进去吧
Ho can handle his own matter, go in!
他们是什么人
Who are they?
当然不会是好人
They're not good
豪哥 老大想请你去叙一叙
Ho, Big Brother wants to see you
我没空
I'm busy
跟我们老大聊几句吧
Talk to me...
豪哥 小马现在在我这里
....
你过来 我们谈谈
Come over too
对不起 我没兴趣
No, thanks I am not interested…
谈生意你就没兴趣
You may not interested in business
难道关于你弟弟的问题
How about your brother?
我等着你的
I waiting...
好
OK!
坚叔 我出去一下
Ken, I want to go out for a while
做人有原则 就什么也不用怕
You have to have principle, don't be afraid
你要坚持呀
Be straight!
豪哥 请
Ho, please!
黑社会这种事 上身容易脱身难呀
You'll never be cleaned once you belong to the underworld
阿豪
Ho,
你回来太好了
so glad you're back
姚叔叔 好吗
How are you, Mr Yiu?
好 你有心了
Fine, thanks
来来来 过来
Come
来 过来跟阿成谈谈
Come, talk to Shing!
不是跟你谈吗
Not you?
跟阿成谈也是一样
It's the same as talking to Shing
我年纪大了 有些事他作主行了
I'm too old to make decisions
豪哥 坐呀
Ho, sit please
现在大把钱赚呀
We can make big money
我真的很希望跟你再合作
I really hope to cooperate with you again
怎么合作
How?
你还是我们的老大
You're still our Big Brother
运伪钞这门路还给小马
Mark handles the trafficking of money
我运我的黑货 一起给公司赚钱
I'll take care of the drugs, make money for our company
有很多老主顾 是要靠你拉拢回来的
We need you to contact the old clients
你还没讲到正题呀
You haven't got to the point yet
如果有你弟弟负责串通警方那条线
With your brother's assistance
那就什么都搞定了
That would be perfect!
有自己人在警方卧底 什么事不能解决呢
What else to have your own man in the police!
来 我有些话要跟你说
Come, I have something to tell you
如果我不答应呢
How about if I don't accept?
豪哥
Ho
我尊重你才收留小马这个废物
I kept Mark because of you
你弟弟不知死活 天天盯着我
Your brother is following everything
我要不是给你面子 他早就死定了
If it wasn't you, he's dead already!
阿成 一个是我朋友 一个是我兄弟
Shing, one is my brother the other is my friend
如果这样我也答应你
How would I walk out this door
我还有面目走出这个门口
if I said yes?
你侮辱我不要紧
It doesn't matter for you to insult me
可千万别侮辱我的朋友
But not my friend
如果你敢动我弟弟分毫
If you hurt my brother
我保证你不会有好日子过
You won't live long
这个杀人重犯马克李
We've wanted Mark Lee
可惜港台之间没有引渡法
But...
要不然
Otherwise,
连带他们的走私集团也一起侦破
we can control the syndicate
台湾警方透过国际刑警
The Roc Police Dept is willing to give information
协助香港警方 负责提供资料
to the Interpol to the Hong Kong Government
同时美国警方已经展开行动
The US Government has also taken action
我明白
I see!
最近我们得到重要的情报
We've some information recently
据说两天之后会有一批伪钞运到台湾
in 2 days there'll be counterfeit shipped to Taiwan
还连带五百公斤吗啡
and 500 kg heroin!
虽然这次不能亲手破案
Though I can't do this case myself
但也希望能看到马克李一伙人得到正法
I hope to see Mark and his men being charged
老大 宋子豪太不给面子了
Boss, Ho is too much
我们杀了他吧
Let's kill him
用不着杀他 不妨跟他玩玩
Not necessary
照计划去做吧
Do as we plan
喂 钱已经付给你了
I gave you the money already
在哪里提货呀
Where do we load the thing?
好 我把地点写给你
I'll give you the address
进去再喝吧
Get in!
回来啦
Come back!
你吃过饭没
Did you have dinner yet?
你干嘛呀你
What are you doing?
莫警司 宋子杰 我找到资料了
Mr Mok, it's Kit, I've got hints
泰国人明天晚上交货给成老大
That Thai will deal with Shing tomorrow
地点跟时间应该是在
Time and location should be…
好 你明天把所有资料拿回来
OK, you hand in the hints tomorrow
其他的事不用你管
and there will be no concern of yours
为什么
Why?
这件案子没你的份儿
You are not involved
我怕你会误了大事
I'm afraid that you'll spoil the whole thing
你给我一个机会好不好
Give me a chance?
局里面是不容许个人英雄的
What are you doing now?
你知不知道今天是我生日呀
Do you know that today is my birthday?
你看我一下好不好
Can you look at me?
就算是一个花瓶放在这里
You'll look
你都会看一下
at vase
这是家里 不是警察局呀
This is your home, not the police barrack
人家的生日你也忘记了
You even forget my birthday
小齐
Jackie
生日快乐
Happy birthday
我没有忘记
I didn't forget
快点吹蜡烛 快要熄灭了
Blow out the candles
许了什么愿
What wish did you make?
你真的想知道我许了个什么愿
You really want to know?
神秘兮兮的
What is it?
不许你发脾气的
Promise not to lose your temper
说吧
Say it
就是希望你们两兄弟能够团叙
The reunion of the two of you
不能生气啊
Don't be angry
没什么
Nothing
不要生气 今天是我生日
Don't get angry on my birthday
不许你发脾气的
I don't let you get angry
不然我可要生气了 笑一笑嘛
Otherwise I will get angry Smile
等我去开
Let me open it
有事吗
Anything happens?
我想跟阿杰说几句话
I want to speak to Kit
谁来了
Who is?
你不许发脾气的
Don't be mad
你答应过我 不发脾气的啊
Keep your promise
坐呀
Sit
行了
Thanks
今天是你生日呀
Today is your birthday?
是呀
Yes
吃块蛋糕
Have a piece of cake
干嘛对他这么好
Why do you treat him that nice?
阿杰 你不要这样嘛
Don't do that
阿杰 我不管你怎么对我
I don't care how you treat me
我能来这里就不怕老实跟你讲
I'm here to tell you that
成老大随时准备陷害你
Shing tries to trap you
你自 己要小心点
Be careful
谢谢你的关心
Thank you!
出来混的人 所讲的话你不要相信
Don't trust those crummy
通常太容易得回来的线索都是假的
It's always a trap if you
你自己要分清楚
have it too easy
你以为我还是以前的阿杰吗
Do you think I am as dumb as before?
我只是想帮你 信不信随便你
I only want to help you
帮我还是害我呀
Help me or trick me?
你相信我一次行不行
Can you trust me one more time?
信你 就连一个老爸也没有了
Trust you?
小齐
Jackie!
豪哥
Ho!
他对我的观感 始终没有改变
His impression of me didn't change a bit
你千万不要放弃 你一定要坚持到底
Don't give up
不要让人看不起
Don't let the other look down upon you
为什么你始终不肯接受他
Why can't you forgive him?
给他一条生路行不行
Let him start a new life?
爸爸是间接给他害死的
He killed dad indirectly?
为什么你还要逼我接受他呢
Why do you force me to accept him
他自己走错了路 怪谁呀
He can't blame anymore for choosing the wrong way?
我是兵 他是贼
I'm the cop, he's the thief
在法律上 我们走的是两条路
We're going opposite
我是警察
I'm a cop
什么事呀 坚叔
What's happening? Ken!
你弟弟受了伤 现在正在动手术
Your brother is having an operation
他现在在玛嘉烈医院
He's now at Queen Margaret's
你尽快赶去吧
Hurry up!
好
OK
我弟弟发生了什么事
What happened to my brother?
看来是中了阿成的圈套
He was trapped by Shing
有心陷害他的
He purposely did it
他伤得怎么样呀
How is he?
你不能进去的
You can't get in
我曾经阻止他单独行动
I tried to stop him alone
可是他一意孤行
But he insisted
我希望你能跟警方合作
I hope you can cooperate with the police
随时让我们知道你的行踪
and let us know your location
要做英雄好容易的 跳下去吧
It's easy to be a hero. Jump
现在时势不同 如果不跟我合作
It's not the same now, you don't have any choice
根本没有第二条路可走
Get along with us
别想向警方通风报讯呀
And don't tell the police
你也知道大家的底子都是不好的
We know each other well
什么事
What's happening?
以后不许你再用宋子豪
Don't use Sung ever again
大家停手
Stop!
跟他们拼啦
Fight with them
停手
Stop it!
有话慢慢说 大家停手呀
Can we make a deal
这么辛苦改邪归正
It's not worthwhile
再犯法坐牢 很不值得
breaking the law again
不要打呀
Stop fighting
停手 你滚蛋
Stop
快走
Run!
你这浑蛋别走呀
You idiot, don't go!
别走 有种的别走
Stay if you have guts!
你们通通滚蛋
You, son of bitch!
坚叔 是我自己不好
Ken. That's my fault
我是不想连累你的
I don't want you to be involved
你这么做就是没有原则
You've no principle
他们心虚才动手打人
They fight because they are scared
你一动手就走回旧路了
If you hit them back then they win
这么辛苦改过自身是为了什么
Why do you want to change?
为了什么
Why?
他是谁 快扶他起来
Who's he?
坚叔 豪哥
Ken! Ho!
快来看呀
Come and have a look
过来
Come over
小马
Mark…
- 豪哥 - 小马
Ho, Mark
不要多说了 快去拿药箱
Emergency box
快拿药箱来呀
Quick!
坚叔 现在怎办呢
Ken, what are we going to do?
你们先走
Let's go!
警察 接受检查
Police. Stop for searching
太过份了吧 警察不讲理的
That's too much
我会寄赔偿单子到警察局的
I'll send the quotation to the Station
你行 走吧
Smart
想不到香港的夜景是这么美的
I didn't notice HK is so beautiful at night
这么美的东西 一下子没有了
But it doesn't last
真是不值得
It's not worthwhile
豪哥
Ho!
我们从头再来过
Let's start all over again
干完最后一票
After this last time
就漂漂亮亮的离开香港
then leave HK gloriously
小马
Mark!
以前的出生入死我们从没害怕过
We've never been scared before
难道这一次我们会怕了阿成吗
Why are we scared of Shing…
不要逼我了 我不会再去的
Don't push me, I'll never get involved again
以前的事 已经过去了
That was the past
没有过去 我还没死
I'm still alive
我让你再做十次 再做一百次
Even you do 10 times, 100 times
又怎么样
Then what?
我让你杀了阿成 那又怎么样
Even you kill Shing?
我已经失去了一个弟弟
I lost my brother already
我不想连你这个朋友也失去了
I don't want to lose you too
小马 你醒一醒好不好
Mark, can you wake up?
你不要可怜我
I don't want sympathy
你没有欠我什么
You didn't owe me anything?
我从来不会逼朋友去做不想做的事
I never force my friend's doing things unwillingly
我有自 己的原则
I've my principle
就是不想一辈子在别人面前低头
I don't want to be a loser for my whole life
你以为我很喜欢跟人乞讨吗
Do you think I like begging?
我倒霉了三年 就是要等一个机会
I've waited for a chance for 3 years
我要争一口气
I've to show them
不是要证明我比别人威风
that I'm not the best
我不见了的东西我自 己一定要拿回来
I...
你看你像什么 你看你自 己像什么
What do you look like?
做坏人的时候给人家骂
We were scared when we were bad
做好人的时候 连走两步也被跟踪
Felt as if we were being followed when we are good
你有争取过机会吗
Did you fight for a chance?
你没有
You didn't
没有呀
No!
我不想跟你一样
I don't want to be like you
小马
Mark!
怎么搞成这样
What happened to you?
我想拿回一些东西
I just want to take back something
站过一边去
Stand over that side
去拿磁带
Go and get the plate
你想清楚没有 这样做会闯大祸的
You'll be in big trouble
不要乱来
Think twice before you do it
暂停 暂停
Stop for a moment
快走呀
Run!
开门
Open the door!
谢谢你 陈伯
Thanks. Mr Chan!
追
Go after them
都是你这个混蛋
You idiot!
我早叫你别玩过火的了
I told you that's too much
你这混蛋
Idiot
如果阿豪把那盒电脑磁带交给警方
If Ho hands the plate to the police
别说你要去跳楼死呀
Not only you will die but
就连我们的组织也要垮了 浑蛋
even the syndicate will collapse
够了
That's enough
左一句浑蛋 右一句浑蛋的
Don't call me idiot
我替你赚钱的时候你怎么叫我呀
What did you call me when I made money for you?
我后悔用错了你
I regret to have you
你要是不把磁带拿回来 我就杀了你
I'll kill you if you don't bring me back the plate
你杀好了
You kill me then
三年前我能够出卖宋子豪
I betrayed Ho 3 years ago
难道三年后我会怕他
Would I be scared of him now?
你会有报应的
You have to pay him back
是你捧我坐这个位置的
We've to share
有祸一起当好了
the problem together!
喂
Hello!
喂 阿豪呀 你可把我给搞惨了
Ho, why did you give me such a problem?
姚叔叔 我要跟阿成谈谈
Mr Yiu. I want to speak to Shing
阿成是吗 你等等
Shing? Wait a minute
你无论如何
Beg him to give
也要求他把磁带还给我们呀
us back the plate
豪哥 不要整我嘛
Ho, don't fool me
有事好商量啊
We can compromise
今天晚上十点
10 p.m. tonight.
你带两百万美金来大庙跟我交换磁带
Go to Temple with US $2,000,000 For the exchange of the plate
然后在西沙湾准备一条船给我
and have a boat ready for you at The Bay
就这么简单
That's simple?
要现金
I want cash
你要亲自带来
You yourself!
我会来
I will be there
阿豪怎么说呀 混蛋 他怎么说呀
What did Ho say? What did he say?
怎么
What?
他说今天晚上来跟你吃饭
He said he wants to have dinner with you
好 我等他
OK, I'll wait for him
- 宋警官 你没事吧 - 没事了
Sir!
宋警官
进来
Come in!
- 局长 - 莫局长
Mr Mok, I've information
有新消息 宋子豪跟马跛子 成老大他们起内讧了
Ho, Mark and Shing have a quarrel
他们要挟成老大一笔钱 准备今天晚上交易
They blackmailed Shing and they're having a deal tonight
知不知道时间地点
Did you know the time and place?
晚一点会再有消息
Later
喂 我是
Hello. I'm…
谢谢
Thanks!
两分钟之前
2 minutes ago
成老大在银行提取了二百万美金出来
Shing debited US $2,000,000 from the bank
全部取消休假
Everyone get ready
- 随时采取行动 - 是
for order
医生不让你出院的
You should be in the hospital
你出来干什么
What are you doing here?
我没事 只是轻伤嘛
I'm fine
放你几天假 回去休息吧
You've a paid leave for a few days
你看 我可以拿起这张椅子
See, I can lift the chair easily
这次行动没你的份儿
You're not included
我哥哥是贼 不是我
My brother is the thief. Not me
我一直按警章办事 为什么不让我去
Why do you give me pressure?
如果你还记得警例
If you still remember the rules
- 就更不应该参加 - 三年前 我爸爸死了
You shouldn't get involved, My dad died 3 years ago
我一直追踪成老大
I allow Shing
整个警察局里最熟这案子的就是我
But you two are brothers
你会不会亲手锁起他
would you lock him up?
我会亲手锁他的 我会
I want to lock him up myself
我一定会亲手锁他的
I'll lock him up
阿杰 现实一点吧
Kit. Be practical
[BGM: 明天会更好]
♪ 谁能不顾自己的家园 抛开记忆中的童年
♪ 谁能忍心看那昨日的忧愁带走我们的笑容
♪ 青春不解红尘  胭脂沾染了灰
♪ 让久违不见的泪水 滋润了你的面容
♪ 唱出你的热情 伸出你的双手 让我拥抱着你的梦
♪ 让我拥有你真心的面孔
♪ 让我们的笑容充满着青春的骄傲…
小齐
Jackie
豪哥
Ho.
我今天晚上离开香港
I'm leaving HK tonight
你这样就放弃
You are giving up
这包东西
Can you give
今天晚上九点以前
this packet
你一定要替我交给阿杰
to Kit tonight at 9
里面的东西对他很重要的
It's very important to him
你还会回来吗？
Will you come back?
♪ 看看忙碌的世界是否依然孤独地转个不停
♪ 日出唤醒清晨 大地光彩重生
♪ 让和风拂出的音响 谱成生命的乐章
♪ 唱出你的热情 伸出你的…
阿杰 你哥哥今天晚上要走了
Kit, your brother is leaving tonight
他叫我交一样很重要的东西给你
He asked me to give this packet to you
阿杰 现在交给你的这盒磁带
Kit. The plate I gave you
是阿成印伪钞的犯罪证据
is the proof to charge Shing
今天晚上我约了阿成在西沙湾谈判
We're having a dealing tonight at The Bay
到时候你要抓我也好 赶我也好
You can put me in prison if you like to
反正我已决定不再留在香港
I decided not to stay in HK
阿杰 你干嘛
What are you doing?
我要去抓他
I have to grab him
不要 你不能抓他的
No. You can't
你不能抓他的
No
走开
Go away!
阿杰
Kit…
阿豪呢 等到菜都凉了
Ho. They are late
你们晓得怎么讲的啦
Do you know what to say?
信不信有神
Do you believe in god?
信 我就是神
I'm the god
神也是人来的
God is a human
能够把握自己的命运 他就是神
Anyone will be god, if he can control his fate
有时候有些事情是把握不到的
But sometimes you couldn't
赌博也有输赢呀
You'll either gain or loose
别动
Hold it!
钱呢
Money?
磁带呢
Plate?
交了给警方
Hand it to the police
不要乱开
Don't
里面有炸弹的
There's a bomb
我也不是好惹的
I'm not a dummy
这样就害怕了
You scared?
那怎么跟我玩下去呀
Don't trick me?
他妈的
Fxxk...
又说要老爷给他两百万
He asked for $2,000,000
今天晚上会在西沙湾出海
He'll be at sea tonight
跟着就听到枪声了
Then I heard a shot
就是他
That's him
你肯定了
Are you sure?
是的
Yes!
你肯不肯做证人
Do you want to be the witness?
肯
Yes!
我早知道你这个浑蛋会这样的
I know you'll do that already
你们输定了
You'll lose
出去
Get out!
Get out…
你们聪明的就快点放人
Let him go if you're smart!
过来呀
Come over
走
Go!
豪哥 下船呀
Ho, on board
你先走吧
You go first
不是说过一起走的吗
You said we'll go together
我还有点事要做
I've something to do
我会跟你会合的
I'll meet you
小马 快开船啊
Mark. Go!
好 我等你
I'll wait for you
你快放人了吧
Release him
否则我杀了你弟弟
Otherwise, I'll kill your brother
你们不要乱来呀
Don't do it
一个换一个
One for one
走呀
Go!
去
我不会放过你的
I won't let you off
我知道
I know!
阿杰
Kit!
过来呀
Come over
你过来
You
这是你的亲哥哥 你多看他两眼
Look at your brother
你看清楚呀
Look!
无论他以前做错了些什么
No matter how he wronged you before
他什么都还给你了
He paid you back now
他有勇气去改过
He has the guts to change
为什么你没勇气去接受呢
What can't you forgive him?
为什么
Why?
做兄弟的
For a brother…
- 阿成 - 哥哥
Shing!
小姐 你不能进去
You can't get over, Miss
阿成
Shing!
宋子豪 你们已经给警方包围了
Ho, you're being surrounded
现在限你们在三分钟之内
In 3 minutes Come out unarmed
放下武器走出来
Drap the...
没有子弹了吗
No more bullets
我现在出去自首
I'm going to surrender
我不会有事的
I'll be alright
你会有事呀
You'll not
我有钱 两三天之后就可以从法庭轻松地出来
I will have money, 3 days later I'll be released
我有钱 黑也可以变成白
I've money, can change black to white
这些 我是跟你学回来的
I learned it from you
你弟弟真可怜
But your brother,
因为你 他是白也变成黑了
because of you, he's from white to black
你害死他了
You've dragged him down
阿杰 你没有错
Kit. You didn't do it wrong
我们走的路不同
We are on different routes
你走的路是对的
Yours is right
以前我走错了
I was wrong before
现在走回正路 也不算太晚吧
I want to be back on the right one now
[BGM: 当年情]
♪ 轻轻笑声 在为我送温暖
♪ 你为我注入快乐强电
♪ 轻轻说声 漫长路快要走过
♪ 终于走过明媚晴天
♪ 声声欢呼跃起 像红日发放金箭
♪ 我伴你往日笑面重现
♪ 轻轻叫声 共抬望眼看高空
♪ 终于青天优美为你献
♪ 拥着你 当初温馨再涌现
♪ 心里边 童年稚气梦未污染
♪ 今日我 与你又试肩并肩
♪ 当年情 此刻是添上新鲜
♪ 一望你 眼里温馨已通电
♪ 心里边 从前梦一点未改变
♪ 今日我 与你又试肩并肩
♪ 当年情……